

Victor Araujo

Salesforce Developer solution architect



victor.araujo@cognizant.com



+351 910327339



https://pt.linkedin.com/in/arjvictorsf

Profile SUMMARY

IT professional over 5 years of experience as a Salesforce Developer, utilizing both agile and waterfall methodologies successfully collaboration on more than 9 projects, including 6 global projects for renowned organizations such as J&J, Reuters, Value Retail, Axon, Enel contributing to large-scale projects. Expertise in working multicultural and multilingual teams in offshore development and consulting operations.

Areas of expertise

- · Salesforce Solution Design
- · Product and Project development
- Teamwork
- Digital transformation
- Discovering Workshops
- User training/education
- · Business process reengineering
- Knowledge sharing
- · Change management

WORK EXPERIENCE -

Cognizant

February 2024 - Present

Snr Salesforce Developer

Developing solutions as a member of the Center of Excellence including communicating with customer to define and clarifying requirements. Managing tasks and moving up backlog tasks while delivering best practices and brilliant new functionalities.

Key Responsibilities:

- Backlog management
- Leadership and Management
- Solution Design and Development

Sowin

March 2022 – Oct 2023

Snr Salesforce Developer

I successfully managed the Salesforce initiatives prioritizing customer care and empowering the business areas to deliver exceptional experiences. Leading crossfunctional teams, guided the ideation and launch of new features, supported collaboration, process improvement, and best practices implementation.

Key Responsibilities:

- · Requirements definition
- Tasks management

Wipro

Sep 2020- Feb 2022

Mid Salesforce Developer

As a Salesforce Developer I enhanced user experience with Aura Components and Lightning Web Components. Utilized Apex for business logic and legacy system integrations. Practiced Agile/Scrum methodologies, alongside DevOps for efficient implementation. This role honed my development skills, collaboration, and problemsolving.

Key Responsibilities:

- Ensuring Success and Mitigating Risks
- Providing Support
- Designing solutions

Deloitte

Jr Salesforce Developer

Mar 2019- Aug 2020

At Deloitte, I started my career as a Salesforce Developer, undergoing a four-month training in Salesforce development. I then joined a specialized team working on streamlining sales and service processes for telecom clients. I developed solutions using Aura Components, Apex, and focused on business logic and integrations. I also contributed to environment configuration and followed Agile/Scrum practices, integrating DevOps. This experience strengthened my skills in agile development, collaboration, and innovative problem-solving.

Key Responsibilities:

- Support technical teams
- Integrating New Features and Architectural Alignment
- Learning Salesforce

Education DETAIL

Post grad 2021- 2022	MBA Solution Architecture
	University FIAP

LANGUAGES ____Technical Skills

Portuguese	Native
English	Good
Spanish	Good

Business Domains: Pharmaceutical, Manufacturing, Military, Energy, Communications, Telecom, Retail, Financial SaaS: Salesforce: service, sales, experience Productivity Tools: Postman, Sf CLI, Sf

Workbench

Functional skills

Functional and business analysis Process analysis and optimization

Product management

Effective communication





